Inventory of Probate case files from District Court (Second District: Weber County), 1851-
Utah State Archives and Records Service
District Court (Second District: Weber County) Probate case files
1851-
Utah State Archives and Records Service 300 South Rio Grande Salt Lake City, UT 84101-1182 801-533-3535 historyresearch@utah.gov
Series 6874
District Court (Second District: Weber County)
331 microfilm reels
Probate case files from the Second District Court in Weber County primarily involve the probate of estates for deceased persons and guardianship for minors and incompetent persons. Probate is judicial oversight of property in transition. Probate of estates is the process by which a deceased person's property is identified and maintained, his debts and taxes paid, and then remaining property distributed to beneficiaries as specified in a will or as required by law for persons who die intestate (without a will). In guardianship cases probate is the establishment of a guardian for minors or incompetent adults who hold property that needs management. In addition to probate these case files also include name changes and some adoptions.
Utah's Territorial Assembly established original jurisdiction over the probate of estates and the guardianship of incompetent persons with county probate courts in 1852 (An Act in Relation to the Judiciary. Acts, Resolutions, and Memorials passed by the First Annual, and Special Sessions of the Legislative Assembly. Great Salt Lake City, 1852, Brigham H. Young, Printer. pp. 38-48). That jurisdiction transferred to the probate divisions of District Courts when County Probate Courts were abolished at statehood.
The probate process includes three parts. First, a petitioner must file with the court the documents necessary to have the court appoint a representative. Documents relating to this process include wills, petitions, letters of administration, bonds, etc., and a court order appointing an administrator, executor, or guardian. Second, the appointed representative does all that is necessary to manage the property through the period of transition. Documents filed here might include a court order appointing appraisers, notices to creditors, estate inventories, various kinds of financial statements, receipts, bills, and the court-appointed representative's final report. Finally, when all requirements have been met, such as all bills paid or a minor has become of age, the court mandates a final settlement and releases the representative from any further responsibility.
The Territorial Legislature made provision for formal adoptions in 1884 and assigned jurisdiction to County Probate Courts (Compiled Laws of Utah, vol. II, 1888, part 5, chapter 4). Adoption case files include a formal petition, documents supporting the petition and the court's final decree. In this series adoption case files begin in 1893. Whereas early adoptions were open to the public and sometimes published in the newspaper, adoptions later became private. Most adoption records in this series are closed to public access (see access restrictions note). In addition to probate and adoption, case files this series also include official name changes.
Gaps in Series
Some missing case files are noted at the beginning of the reel, i.e., reel 178.
Research Note
Evidently the current probate case numbering system began approximately 1897. When cases originally filed with the Weber County Probate Court (between 1851 and 1896) were transferred to the district court, the territorial cases as well as those filed during the first year of statehood were assigned numbers presumably based on an existing alphabetic arrangement (cases 1-671). Since the adoption of the current numbering system, cases filed in the district court have been assigned numbers according to the date of filing. For most probate cases filed since statehood it is advisable to obtain the file number from the Weber County District Court Clerk in order to use the archives's microfilm copies of the case files effectively. Reference service on probate cases filed from 1970 to the present is provided exclusively by the Court Clerk.
Numerical by case number.
These records are public with the exception of adoption records, which are sealed for 100 years according to Utah Code Annotated 87-19-4 (1953), and commitment proceedings, which are classified by the Administrative Office of the Court as private (Code of Judicial Administration, Rule 4-202, section 3 [G] [iii]). Since restricted information is recorded together with public information, the series must be searched for patrons by staff members. Contact a reference archivist for more information.
The Weber County Clerk was constitutionally designated as ex-officio clerk of Second District Court in and for Weber County until 1989 when the state assumed full financial and administrative responsibility for the district court. At that time a new court clerk was appointed. The probate case files were microfilmed by the Weber County District Court Clerk at regular intervals beginning in 1973. Reference copies were provided to the Utah State Archives.
These records were acquired from the creating agency through established retention schedules.
Other: a research guide is available for public use. Indexes: a one-page index listing 17 individuals in alphabetic order precedes the "Ancient" files on reel 1, covering from 1851 thru 1879, and from 1 thru 17. Indexes: a general index to Weber County Probate Court business (series 21023) includes 810 probate cases. This volume (identified as Index Book 1) is the only index to Weber County probate matters which has been transferred to the archives, covering from 1 thru 810. Indexes: a comprehensive index is available from the court clerk, covering from 1851 thru 1988, and from 1 thru 17147.
Probate minute books from Weber County (Utah). Probate Court, Series 5142, document proceedings in probate matters.
Probate record books from the District Court (Second District: Weber County), Series 6405, document proceedings in probate matters.
Probate case files from the District Court (Second District: Weber County), Series 17532, record case numbers as well as a summary of actions.
Probate Court index from the District Court (Second District: Weber County), Series 21023, provides the names of parties in probate actions and provides assigned estate numbers for cases 1-810.
Probate registers of action from the District Court (Second District: Weber County), Series 26955, contains the complete case files cited throughout these record books.
Probate registers index from the District Court (Second District: Weber County), Series 26956, contains the complete case files cited throughout these record books.
Politics, Government, and Law
Adoption--Utah--Weber County.; Guardian and ward--Utah--Weber County.; Executors and administrators--Utah--Weber County.; Probate records--Utah--Weber County.
- Probate case files, 1851-; 331 microfilm reels
  - 1-17, 1851-1879 (Reel 1)
  - 1-12, 1851-1897 (Reel 2)
  - 13-30, 1851-1897 (Reel 3)
  - 31-43, 1851-1897 (Reel 4)
  - 44-56, 1851-1897 (Reel 5)
  - 57-69, 1851-1897 (Reel 6)
  - 70-82, 1851-1897 (Reel 7)
  - 83-101, 1851-1897 (Reel 8)
  - 102-120, 1851-1897 (Reel 9)
  - 121-139, 1851-1897 (Reel 10)
  - 140-150, 1851-1897 (Reel 11)
  - 151-165, 1851-1897 (Reel 12)
  - 166-185, 1851-1897 (Reel 13)
  - 186-203, 1851-1897 (Reel 14)
  - 204-216, 1851-1897 (Reel 15)
  - 217-229, 1851-1897 (Reel 16)
  - 230-245, 1851-1897 (Reel 17)
  - 246-258, 1851-1897 (Reel 18)
  - 259-266, 1851-1897 (Reel 19)
  - 267-280, 1851-1897 (Reel 20)
  - 281-291, 1851-1897 (Reel 21)
  - 292-299, 1851-1897 (Reel 22)
  - 300-315, 1851-1897 (Reel 23)
  - 316-338, 1851-1897 (Reel 24)
  - 339-348, 1851-1897 (Reel 25)
  - 349-361, 1851-1897 (Reel 26)
  - 362-373, 1851-1897 (Reel 27)
  - 374-387, 1851-1897 (Reel 28)
  - 388-398, 1851-1897 (Reel 29)
  - 399-412, 1851-1897 (Reel 30)
  - 413-421, 1851-1897 (Reel 31)
  - 422-500, 1851-1897 (Reel 32)
  - 501-519, 1851-1897 (Reel 33)
  - 520-531, 1851-1897 (Reel 34)
  - 532-550, 1851-1897 (Reel 35)
  - 551-566, 1851-1897 (Reel 36)
  - 567-582, 1851-1897 (Reel 37)
  - 583-595, 1851-1897 (Reel 38)
  - 596-610, 1851-1897 (Reel 39)
  - 611-628, 1851-1897 (Reel 40)
  - 629-646, 1851-1897 (Reel 41)
  - 647-655, 1851-1897 (Reel 42)
  - 656-667, 1851-1897 (Reel 43)
  - 667-669, 1851-1897 (Reel 44)
  - 669-687, 1897 (Reel 45)
  - 688-700, 1897 (Reel 46)
  - 701-722, 1897 (Reel 47)
  - 723-734, 1897-1898 (Reel 48)
  - 735-753, 1898 (Reel 49)
  - 754-767, 1898 (Reel 50)
  - 768-783, 1898-1899 (Reel 51)
  - 784-809, 1899 (Reel 52)
  - 810-829, 1899 (Reel 53)
  - 830-858, 1899-1900 (Reel 54)
  - 859-877, 1900 (Reel 55)
  - 878-890, 1900 (Reel 56)
  - 891-906, 1900 (Reel 57)
  - 907-927, 1900-1901 (Reel 58)
  - 928-944, 1901 (Reel 59)
  - 945-965, 1901 (Reel 60)
  - 966-984, 1901 (Reel 61)
  - 985-1002, 1901-1902 (Reel 62)
  - 1003-1026, 1902 (Reel 63)
  - 1027-1050, 1902 (Reel 64)
  - 1051-1070, 1902 (Reel 65)
  - 1071-1094, 1902 (Reel 66)
  - 1095-1107, 1902-1903 (Reel 67)
  - 1108-1122, 1903 (Reel 68)
  - 1123-1134, 1903 (Reel 69)
  - 1134-1156, 1903 (Reel 70)
  - 1157-1171, 1903 (Reel 71)
  - 1172-1185, 1903-1904 (Reel 72)
  - 1186-1206, 1904 (Reel 73)
  - 1206-1228, 1904 (Reel 74)
  - 1229-1252, 1904 (Reel 75)
  - 1253-1271, 1904 (Reel 76)
  - 1271-1289, 1904 (Reel 77)
  - 1290-1306, 1904-1905 (Reel 78)
  - 1307-1328, 1905 (Reel 79)
  - 1329-1346, 1905 (Reel 80)
  - 1347-1360, 1905 (Reel 81)
  - 1360-1365, 1905 (Reel 82)
  - 1366-1379, 1905-1906 (Reel 83)
  - 1380-1400, 1906 (Reel 84)
  - 1401-1411, 1906 (Reel 85)
  - 1412-1428, 1906 (Reel 86)
  - 1429-1447, 1906 (Reel 87)
  - 1448-1467, 1906 (Reel 88)
  - 1468-1487, 1906-1907 (Reel 89)
  - 1488-1504, 1907 (Reel 90)
  - 1505-1522, 1907 (Reel 91)
  - 1523-1542, 1907 (Reel 92)
  - 1543-1560, 1907 (Reel 93)
  - 1560-1574, 1907 (Reel 94)
  - 1575-1590, 1907 (Reel 95)
  - 1591-1616, 1907-1908 (Reel 96)
  - 1617-1636, 1908 (Reel 97)
  - 1637-1652, 1908 (Reel 98)
  - 1653-1674, 1908 (Reel 99)
  - 1675-1680, 1908 (Reel 100)
  - 1681-1697, 1908 (Reel 101)
  - 1698-1718, 1908-1909 (Reel 102)
  - 1719-1736, 1909 (Reel 103)
  - 1737-1746, 1909 (Reel 104)
  - 1747-1766, 1909 (Reel 105)
  - 1767-1779, 1909 (Reel 106)
  - 1779-1797, 1909 (Reel 107)
  - 1798-1817, 1909 (Reel 108)
  - 1818-1827, 1909 (Reel 109)
  - 1828-1842, 1909-1910 (Reel 110)
  - 1843-1855, 1910 (Reel 111)
  - 1856-1870, 1910 (Reel 112)
  - 1871-1897, 1910 (Reel 113)
  - 1898-1915, 1910 (Reel 114)
  - 1915-1930, 1910 (Reel 115)
  - 1931-1947, 1910 (Reel 116)
  - 1948-1963, 1910-1911 (Reel 117)
  - 1964-1985, 1911 (Reel 118)
  - 1986-2006, 1911 (Reel 119)
  - 2007-2019, 1911 (Reel 120)
  - 2019-2038, 1911 (Reel 121)
  - 2039-2059, 1911 (Reel 122)
  - 2060-2076, 1911-1912 (Reel 123)
  - 2077-2091, 1912 (Reel 124)
  - 2092-2115, 1912 (Reel 125)
  - 2116-2130, 1912 (Reel 126)
  - 2131-2152, 1912-1913 (Reel 127)
  - 2153-2168, 1913 (Reel 128)
  - 2169, 1913 (Reel 129)
  - 2169-2179, 1913 (Reel 130)
  - 2180-2198, 1913 (Reel 131)
  - 2198-2211, 1913 (Reel 132)
  - 2212-2228, 1913 (Reel 133)
  - 2229-2239, 1913 (Reel 134)
  - 2240-2254, 1913 (Reel 135)
  - 2255-2267, 1913 (Reel 136)
  - 2268-2292, 1913-1914 (Reel 137)
  - 2293-2312, 1914 (Reel 138)
  - 2313-2334, 1914 (Reel 139)
  - 2335-2358, 1914 (Reel 140)
  - 2359-2378, 1914 (Reel 141)
  - 2379-2384, 1914 (Reel 142)
  - 2385-2404, 1914-1915 (Reel 143)
  - 2405-2428, 1915 (Reel 144)
  - 2429-2455, 1915 (Reel 145)
  - 2456-2471, 1915 (Reel 146)
  - 2472-2497, 1915 (Reel 147)
  - 2498-2517, 1915-1916 (Reel 148)
  - 2518-2532, 1916 (Reel 149)
  - 2533-2549, 1916 (Reel 150)
  - 2550-2566, 1916 (Reel 151)
  - 2566-2577, 1916 (Reel 152)
  - 2578-2598, 1916 (Reel 153)
  - 2599-2616, 1916 (Reel 154)
  - 2617-2653, 1916 (Reel 155)
  - 2654-2702, 1916-1917 (Reel 156)
  - 2703-2733, 1917 (Reel 157)
  - 2734-2786, 1917 (Reel 158)
  - 2787-2837, 1917-1918 (Reel 159)
  - 2838-2881, 1918 (Reel 160)
  - 2882-2911, 1918 (Reel 161)
  - 2912-2944, 1918 (Reel 162)
  - 2945-2981, 1918-1919 (Reel 163)
  - 2982-3028, 1919 (Reel 164)
  - 3029-3072, 1919 (Reel 165)
  - 3073-3115, 1919 (Reel 166)
  - 3116-3196, 1919-1920 (Reel 167)
  - 3170-3219, 1920 (Reel 168)
  - 3220-3258, 1920 (Reel 169)
  - 3258-3285, 1920 (Reel 170)
  - 3286-3316, 1920 (Reel 171)
  - 3317-3357, 1920-1921 (Reel 172)
  - 3358-3394, 1921 (Reel 173)
  - 3394-3418, 1921 (Reel 174)
  - 3419-3449, 1921 (Reel 175)
  - 3450-3495, 1921 (Reel 176)
  - 3496-3539, 1921-1922 (Reel 177)
  - 3541-3606, 1922 (Reel 178)
  - 3607-3617, 1922 (Reel 179)
  - 3618-3663, 1922 (Reel 180)
  - 3664-3709, 1922-1923 (Reel 181)
  - 3710-3745, 1923 (Reel 182)
  - 3745-3803, 1923 (Reel 183)
  - 3804-3844, 1923 (Reel 184)
  - 3845-3901, 1923 (Reel 185)
  - 3902-3939, 1924 (Reel 186)
  - 3939-3995, 1924 (Reel 187)
  - 3996-4026, 1924-1925 (Reel 188)
  - 4026-4085, 1925 (Reel 189)
  - 4085-4135, 1925 (Reel 190)
  - 4138-4172, 1925-1926 (Reel 191)
  - 4172-4218, 1926 (Reel 192)
  - 4219-4261, 1926 (Reel 193)
  - 4261-4315, 1926-1927 (Reel 194)
  - 4316-4335, 1927 (Reel 195)
  - 4335-4394, 1927 (Reel 196)
  - 4395-4437, 1927 (Reel 197)
  - 4438-4490, 1928 (Reel 198)
  - 4490-4519, 1928 (Reel 199)
  - 4519-4564, 1928 (Reel 200)
  - 4564-4617, 1928 (Reel 201)
  - 4618-4657, 1929 (Reel 202)
  - 4658-4712, 1929 (Reel 203)
  - 4712-4741, 1929 (Reel 204)
  - 4742-4763, 1929 (Reel 205)
  - 4763-4791, 1930 (Reel 206)
  - 4791-4849, 1930 (Reel 207)
  - 4849-4899, 1930 (Reel 209)
  - 4899-4930, 1930 (Reel 209)
  - 4930-4974, 1930 (Reel 210)
  - 4974-5027, 1931 (Reel 211)
  - 5027-5087, 1931 (Reel 212)
  - 5088-5128, 1931 (Reel 213)
  - 5129-5177, 1932 (Reel 214)
  - 5178-5225, 1932 (Reel 215)
  - 5225-5274, 1932 (Reel 216)
  - 5275-5340, 1933 (Reel 217)
  - 5340-5368, 1934 (Reel 218)
  - 5368-5421, 1934 (Reel 219)
  - 5422-5481, 1934 (Reel 220)
  - 5482-5526, 1934 (Reel 221)
  - 5527-5592, 1934-1935 (Reel 222)
  - 5592-5632, 1935 (Reel 223)
  - 5632-5697, 1935 (Reel 224)
  - 5698-5759, 1937 (Reel 225)
  - 5760-5817, 1937 (Reel 226)
  - 5818-5892, 1937 (Reel 227)
  - 5893-5961, 1937 (Reel 228)
  - 5962-6029, 1937 (Reel 229)
  - 6029-6084, 1937-1938 (Reel 230)
  - 6084-6130, 1938 (Reel 231)
  - 6130-6195, 1938-1939 (Reel 232)
  - 6195-6250, 1939 (Reel 233)
  - 6251-6316, 1939-1940 (Reel 234)
  - 6317-6398, 1940 (Reel 235)
  - 6398-6472, 1940-1942 (Reel 236)
  - 6473-6541, 1941 (Reel 237)
  - 6542-6614, 1941 (Reel 238)
  - 6615-6678, 1942 (Reel 239)
  - 6679-6752, 1942 (Reel 240)
  - 6753-6802, 1943 (Reel 241)
  - 6803-6875, 1943 (Reel 242)
  - 6876-6951, 1943 (Reel 243)
  - 6952-7028, 1944 (Reel 244)
  - 7029-7084, 1944 (Reel 245)
  - 7085-7156, 1945 (Reel 246)
  - 7157-7228, 1945 (Reel 247)
  - 7229-7288, 1945 (Reel 248)
  - 7289-7351, 1945-1946 (Reel 249)
  - 7352-7408, 1946 (Reel 250)
  - 7408-7453, 1946 (Reel 251)
  - 7453-7518, 1946 (Reel 252)
  - 7519-7561, 1947 (Reel 253)
  - 7561-7612, 1947 (Reel 254)
  - 7612-7669, 1947 (Reel 255)
  - 7669-7723, 1947 (Reel 256)
  - 7723-7775, 1947 (Reel 257)
  - 7776-7837, 1948 (Reel 258)
  - 7838-7896, 1948 (Reel 259)
  - 7897-7951, 1948 (Reel 260)
  - 7952-8015, 1949 (Reel 261)
  - 8016-8079, 1949 (Reel 262)
  - 8080-8144, 1949 (Reel 263)
  - 8145-8206, 1950 (Reel 264)
  - 8207-8269, 1950 (Reel 265)
  - 8269-8332, 1951 (Reel 266)
  - 8332-8388, 1951 (Reel 267)
  - 8388-8456, 1951-1952 (Reel 268)
  - 8456-8504, 1952 (Reel 269)
  - 8505-8567, 1952 (Reel 270)
  - 8568-8635, 1952 (Reel 271)
  - 8636-8714, 1952-1953 (Reel 272)
  - 8714-8780, 1953 (Reel 273)
  - 8780-8852, 1953-1954 (Reel 274)
  - 8853-8914, 1954 (Reel 275)
  - 8914-8974, 1954 (Reel 276)
  - 8974-9046, 1954 (Reel 277)
  - 9047-9121, 1955 (Reel 278)
  - 9122-9198, 1955-1956 (Reel 279)
  - 9199-9254, 1956 (Reel 280)
  - 9255-9320, 1956 (Reel 281)
  - 9321-9386, 1956 (Reel 282)
  - 9387-9450, 1957 (Reel 283)
  - 9450-9503, 1957 (Reel 284)
  - 9504-9574, 1957 (Reel 285)
  - 9575-9623, 1958 (Reel 286)
  - 9624-9693, 1958 (Reel 287)
  - 9694-9755, 1958 (Reel 288)
  - 9756-9816, 1958 (Reel 289)
  - 9817-9867, 1959 (Reel 290)
  - 9868-9927, 1959 (Reel 291)
  - 9928-9978, 1959 (Reel 292)
  - 9979-10027, 1960 (Reel 293)
  - 10028-10096, 1960 (Reel 294)
  - 10096-10146, 1960 (Reel 295)
  - 10147-10186, 1960 (Reel 296)
  - 10187-10241, 1961 (Reel 297)
  - 10242-10311, 1961 (Reel 298)
  - 10312-10367, 1961 (Reel 299)
  - 10368-10422, 1961 (Reel 300)
  - 10423-10475, 1962 (Reel 301)
  - 10476-10531, 1962 (Reel 302)
  - 10532-10589, 1963 (Reel 303)
  - 10590-10654, 1962 (Reel 304)
  - 10654-10714, 1962 (Reel 305)
  - 10715-10777, 1963 (Reel 306)
  - 10778-10839, 1963 (Reel 307)
  - 10840-10882, 1963 (Reel 308)
  - 10883-10925, 1964 (Reel 309)
  - 10926-10978, 1964 (Reel 310)
  - 10978-11036, 1964 (Reel 311)
  - 11036-11099, 1964 (Reel 312)
  - 11099-11150, 1964 (Reel 313)
  - 11151-11188, 1965 (Reel 314)
  - 11188-11256, 1965 (Reel 315)
  - 11257-11314, 1965 (Reel 316)
  - 11315-11359, 1966 (Reel 317)
  - 11360-11425, 1966 (Reel 318)
  - 11426-11477, 1966 (Reel 319)
  - 11478-11539, 1966 (Reel 320)
  - 11540-11597, 1967 (Reel 321)
  - 11597-11669, 1967 (Reel 322)
  - 11670-11725, 1967 (Reel 323)
  - 11726-11783, 1967 (Reel 324)
  - 11784-11859, 1968 (Reel 325)
  - 11860-11912, 1968 (Reel 326)
  - 11913-11981, 1968 (Reel 327)
  - 11982-12129, 1968 (Reel 328)
  - 12030-12107, 1968 (Reel 329)
  - 12108-12139, 1969 (Reel 330)
  - 12140-12196, 1969 (Reel 331)
  - 12196-12224, 1969-1970 (Reel 330)